After 200 years, the truth behind the legend.
The Bounty is a action, drama, history film directed by Roger Donaldson.
An idyllic voyage to Tahiti in 1789 turns a crew aboard the H.M.S.
Bounty against its captain when they find a tropical paradise.
Fletcher Christian, played by Mel Gibson.
Lieutenant  William Bligh, played by Anthony Hopkins.
John Fryer, played by Daniel Day-Lewis.
William Cole, played by Bernard Hill.
Charles Churchill, played by Liam Neeson.
Edward Young, played by Phil Davis.
The Bounty is a 1984 British epic historical drama
film directed by Roger Donaldson.
It depicts the voyage and mutiny of HMS Bounty, with Robert Bolt's
screenplay adapting the 1972 book Captain Bligh and Mr.
Christian by Richard Hough.
It stars Mel Gibson as Fletcher Christian and Anthony Hopkins as William Bligh, with supporting roles
played by Laurence Olivier, Daniel Day-Lewis, Liam Neeson, Bernard Hill and Edward Fox.
The Bounty began production in late 1978 under director David Lean as a long-time passion project, but multiple complications, including a prohibitively high budget and
screenwriter Robert Bolt suffering from a heart attack, led to a period of development hell that ended with the hiring of newcomer director Donaldson.
Filming took place primarily on-location in Donaldson's home
country of New Zealand, French Polynesia and England.
The film was made by Dino De Laurentiis Productions and Bounty Productions Ltd.
and distributed by Thorn EMI Screen Entertainment in the UK,
and Orion Pictures Corporation internationally.
It premiered on 4 May 1984 and received generally positive reviews, with praise for Hopkins' portrayal of Bligh, and was noted by critics and historians as
being a more historically accurate depiction of the mutiny than previous depictions, though reactions to Gibson's performance were more polarised.
The Bounty was entered into the 1984 Cannes Film Festival,
where it was nominated for the Palme d’Or.
The film explores themes of sea, ship, exotic island, mutiny, lake.
The tone is emotional.